<bibdata type="standard" schema-version="v1.2.8">
  <fetched>2024-05-30</fetched>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">OGC® Geospatial User Feedback Standard: XML Encoding Extension</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">OGC® Geospatial User Feedback Standard: XML Encoding Extension</title>
  <uri type="src">http://www.opengis.net/doc/IS/guf-xml/1.0.0</uri>
  <uri type="obp">https://docs.ogc.org/is/15-098r1/15-098r1.html</uri>
  <docidentifier type="OGC" primary="true">15-098r1</docidentifier>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2016-12-22</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="author"/>
    <person>
      <name>
        <completename>Joan Masó and Lucy Bastin </completename>
      </name>
    </person>
  </contributor>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Open Geospatial Consortium</name>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <edition>1</edition>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">The Geospatial User Feedback XML encoding standard is based on the OGC Geospatial User Feedback conceptual model [OGC 15-097]. Geospatial User Feedback (GUF) is metadata that is predominantly produced by the consumers of geospatial data products based on their use and experience with those products. This standard complements the existing metadata conventions whereby documents recording dataset characteristics and production workflows are generated by the creator, publisher, or curator of a data product. As a part of metadata, the GUF data model internally reuses some elements of ISO 19115-1 (the updated version of the OGC Abstract Specification Topic 11) but not the general structure. This selective use of ISO metadata elements prioritizes future interoperability with developing ISO metadata models.
This standard can be used in combination with the OGC 15-097 Conceptual Model Standard. In the future, other encodings may be considered, being an alternative using the JSON-LD encoding based on parts of schema.org.
</abstract>
  <ext schema-version="v1.0.1">
    <doctype>standard</doctype>
    <subdoctype>implementation</subdoctype>
    <editorialgroup>
      <committee>technical</committee>
    </editorialgroup>
  </ext>
</bibdata>